WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
JONATHAN LAPAGLIA: 12 Titans
at the top of their game...
VIOLA: Titans are a force
to be reckoned with.
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Yeah!
A tribe of need leaders.
Come on, boys!
(CHEERING)
..took on 12 Rebels...
(SHOUTING)
..determined to play
by their own rules...
(CHEERING)
It was perfect Rebel behaviour.
I was way too freaking rebellious!
Om.
..each ready to outwit...
A bloody idol, baby! (LAUGHS)
My idol has saved me through more
than a dozen Tribal Councils.
Did Ray just fake-find the idol?
They don't vote with us,
then Caroline goes home.
Yeah.
Because I will vote with them.
I'm delivering my first blindside.
And guess what? It's a baby girl.
..outplay...
I'm gonna demolish everyone.
My vote tonight is the weakest
link in our tribe.
They say that Val fights
wolves in Russia,
but wolves are just puppy dogs
compared to me.
..and outlast.
We have a showdown
between Mark and Feras.
Yes! Whoo-hoo!
This could be
a half-million-dollar shot.
Yeah!
Mark takes individual immunity again!
From fierce rivalries...
(LAUGHS)
Now, you tried to get me again.
I did, I did.
In the mafia, if somebody goes
for the boss,
like, you've got to take them out.
My alliance and Feras's alliance
are gunning for each other.
Kirby, right now,
is bloody untouchable.
I think that we have too many people
in this tribe that are scared
to write her name down.
Just leave my name out of it.
..they formed loyal alliances.
I want to try to find a way
to come back together.
Mm-hm.
I, as a former diplomat,
bring people together.
New beginnings.
New beginnings, new beginnings.
Kirby feels like an older sister.
We think alike.
Who would you want to sit
next to at the end?
You, Ri, or Kitty?
Serious?
I want to beat the best of the best.
And after 45 days...
You're all about to really hate me.
Oh, no way!
Valeria.
OTHERS: Oh!
..and countless blindsides...
I'm going to play it for Mark.
Thank you.
Tonight I'm backing myself.
I'd like to play this for me.
Kirby, the tribe has spoken.
They have.
..the final three...
Feras could have saved Kirby.
He had an idol.
He didn't play it for her.
It has been a regret of mine.
If I'd kept Kirby, she would be
wearing that necklace today, 100%.
..were decided by fire.
Caroline wins her position
in the final three.
Well done.
Argh!
Raymond, the tribe has spoken.
Three are left.
Who will become Sole Survivor?
FERAS: I feel extremely numb.
(CAROLINE CHUCKLES)
I've lost everything.
I chose to back myself.
And when it comes to challenges...
..I've fallen extremely short.
I have not won a single
individual immunity.
And I know Mark's extremely tough
when it comes to his mental state.
But I'm gonna dig deep.
I'm going to be thinking of my wife
and everyone back home
in Western Sydney,
and I want to make sure
I make them all proud.
My back's against the wall now.
I've got no other choice.
It's either win today's
challenge or go home.
I'm in trouble.
MARK: Dreams can come true.
It is day 46 on Survivor,
and I am the top three.
Last night at Tribal Council,
we sent Ray packing to the jury
in a fire-making challenge,
and I landed some big right hooks
on Feras's chin.
It was a great feeling for me.
I've totally rattled him.
I came to this game
as a former diplomat.
I used all of my skills -
I analysed, I strategised,
and, at times, I put aside
my personal feelings
to get enemies to work together.
That is diplomacy 101.
But the fact that I haven't
been afraid to instigate conflict
proves that I am a ruthless player,
and I will destroy anyone
to win this game.
It's been 46 days of blood, sweat
and tears, out here on this island.
I've won two immunity challenges
in a row,
and now I am gonna win this final
immunity challenge.
The time for diplomacy is over.
All that remains is me going to war.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYS)
CAROLINE: Being an older woman,
I know that my tribe might
have looked at me
as a weak link.
They all underestimated me.
But I've been playing the long game.
When I have a goal in mind,
I will do everything to get there,
and I don't think
that they expect that in me.
I took out massive threats.
I split up power couples.
I wasn't going to let anything
get in the way
of me getting to here, right now.
We've got two Titans and one Rebel.
And today, it's all going to hinge
on this final immunity challenge.
I know that if I don't win it,
Mark will take me to the final two.
The power lies with Mark and I...
..so Feras better watch out.
Oh, dear Lord.
(CREAKING)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYS)
Come on in.
(VOCALISING)
Congratulations.
You've made it to day 46.
And to get this far, you've survived
a clash of Titans and Rebels,
in a season that has produced
some of the most intense
and unpredictable gameplay
we've ever seen,
so well done.
Thank you, JLP.
Thank you. Thank you.
Now, are you ready to get
to your final immunity challenge?
Yes.
Alright.
Here, JLP.
Thank you, Mark.
For the last time, immunity
is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge...
..you're gonna stand on narrow pegs
fixed to a giant wheel.
At regular intervals,
the wheel will turn...
(WHEEL CREAKS)
..forcing you onto narrower pegs.
If at any point
you come off the wheel,
you're out of the challenge.
Last person left standing
wins immunity and is guaranteed
a spot at that final Tribal Council,
where you will have a chance to pitch
to the jury why you deserve
the title of Sole Survivor
and the half a million dollars
that goes with it.
Yeah.
In addition, you'll also get
to decide who will be sitting
next to you at that Tribal Council.
Now, there's a lot on the line,
and this is a tough challenge.
So, we figured that you might need
a little extra motivation
from some loved ones.
Oh.
Mark, who are you hoping
to see today?
My wife, Sas.
(CRIES, LAUGHS)
Oh, my gosh!
I'm doing good.
Give me a kiss. Sorry, I probably
stink. Come on over.
No, you're fine.
Come meet my mates.
Oh, my gosh, yes.
This is JLP.
Hi.
And this is Feras and Caroline.
Hi!
Hey, Sas.
Nice to meet you.
He and I have had our ups and downs,
but we love each other, right now.
(LAUGHTER)
Sorry!
So, Mark, how does it feel seeing
Saskia for the first time in 46 days?
It's just so special to have her
here right now.
There's no one else I want here
more than Sas.
I'm going to have to have the fight
of my life on that thing.
And I know that Sas is going
to give me the strength to win.
That's what I need right now.
Just so glad you're here.
Can't stop looking at you.
I know, look at me.
(ALL LAUGH)
Alright, Caroline, are you ready
for some love?
Oh, Jonathan. Yep.
Come on in.
(BOTH CRY, LAUGH)
It's so good to see you.
Yeah.
Yeah, last night was crazy.
Oh, yeah.
This is my husband, Murray.
Hi, really nice to meet you.
Yes, hello.
Oh.
Wow.
So, Murray, when Caroline
came to you and said,
"You know, I'm just going to go
and play Survivor,"
what did you think?
Um...
..I think I started off with,
like, "What, seriously?"
And this is a person who loves
a silk pillow,
an eye mask, earplugs
and a really puffy, comfortable bed.
But she just wanted to prove
to herself, I think,
that she could get outside
of her comfort zone
and actually do this.
So, I mean, I'm not surprised
that she's here,
and I'm not surprised
that she's done really well.
He knows how much I wanted
to be here.
So to have him here and know
that he's very proud of me,
yeah, it's amazing! (LAUGHS)
Certainly is.
Alright, Feras, I know
that you've been missing home.
Who are you hoping to see?
Um... (CRIES) ..my wife.
I'm dying to see her.
Alright, come on in.
Oh. (LAUGHS)
(BOTH CRY)
Stop.
Look how skinny I am.
(LAUGHTER)
Oh, my God.
I'm literally shaking.
Guys...
Oh, my God, hi.
..this is my lovely wife, Iman.
Oh, my God, I missed you so much.
Oh, wow.
Feras, how much have you missed
your wife?
She's all I've ever thought
about this whole time.
She's the reason why I kept pushing.
She's the reason why I was
so cutthroat in this game.
She's literally the reason
why I'm here. Yeah.
He's done so well.
I'm so, so proud of him.
Well, Feras has made no secret
that he's playing this game
for his community.
Do you think he makes
a good role model?
Definitely.
Yeah.
I can wholeheartedly say that.
Alright, loved ones, clearly
everyone is happy to see you.
And we're happy that you've come
here to support them,
but you're going to be doing it
from the bench today.
I'm going to give everyone
a minute to catch up.
And then, Caroline, Feras and Mark,
we're going to get to it.
Love you.
Good luck.
Really?
Alright, everyone,
take up your positions.
You can do this.
They're not...they're not big pegs,
hey?
Alright, everyone is in position.
And for final immunity...
..this challenge is now on.
If you only win one challenge
this season, this is it.
This is the one where you want
to push in all your chips.
Could be a half-million-dollar
challenge.
No pressure.
I'm already bloody sweating.
Uh-oh.
It's boiling.
(SIGHS)
Yeah, the fire would make it
so much worse.
It's only gonna get worse.
(LAUGHS)
(VOCALISING)
(WHEELS CREAK)
Alright, you have been up there
for 10 minutes.
This first set of pegs
are the easy ones.
That's the warm up.
Get you used to things
before we move on.
You need to stand on the pegs
below you, but you can hold
any of the four that are above you.
You can do this.
At regular intervals,
the wheel will turn, forcing you
onto narrower pegs.
Those pegs are going to start
grinding into the soles
of your feet.
FERAS: Luckily, my best friend's
a podiatrist.
(LAUGHTER)
How's everyone feeling?
Good.
Cushy.
What about for you, Feras?
You're a little heavier.
You reckon?
Yeah, this is the 'Feras' wheel!
(LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHS)
We've had so much fun, Marky Mark.
We have.
Yeah.
We've been together since day one.
Wow.
A lot has happened. (LAUGHS)
I've hated him. I've loved him.
I've hated him.
He's tried to vote me off.
(LAUGHTER)
And I think I wrote
both your names down.
(LAUGHTER)
Sorry, guys!
I haven't actually voted for you,
Feras.
Well, hopefully,
tonight's not the night.
(LAUGHTER)
Alright,
you've been up there for 40 minutes.
How hot is that, Marky?
(BLEEP)...hot.
Shall we turn up the heat?
Yeah.
Sure.
Yep.
In a moment, I'm gonna rotate
these wheels, and you'll need
to take up position
on the next set of pegs.
But it is a live transition,
so if you fall while I'm rotating,
you are out of the challenge.
Here we go.
(LEVER CREAKS)
(WHEELS CREAK)
Ooh, that's good.
Everyone in the second position.
Those pegs are 10mm smaller
than the previous ones.
You've got fewer hand positions now.
Careful, babe.
Definitely looks a little more
awkward.
So, Feras, as the only Rebel left,
do you think you need to win
this one today?
Yeah. No, it's essential
that I win this.
What about you, Mark?
Do you think Feras needs to win it?
Well, I want to win it.
And I've had a taste of it
and I want it again.
Tastes pretty good, right?
It's real good.
Tastes very good.
So, Feras, what do you think's
going to get you today?
Is it going to be the boredom of
being up there,
or is it going to be those pegs
grinding into your feet?
I can deal with pain.
I've popped out a shoulder,
I've broken a shoulder.
I'm fine with pain.
Caroline, it sounds like
you have a fight on your hands.
I've given birth to three children.
Nice!
(LAUGHTER)
Labour can be long.
Never underestimate a woman.
Yeah.
That's why she's a Titan.
You've been up there for one hour.
You're doing amazing.
Yeah.
You got it, darling.
Lots of shifting around from Feras
and Mark.
Meanwhile...
..Caroline's in the zone.
Locked and loaded.
Is this position just too easy?
Do what you need to do.
Alright, let's go.
Oh.
Lots of shifting around
from everyone.
You've got this.
Mark, is it getting a little more
difficult to find something
comfortable?
Yeah.
It is those narrow pegs
that will get you in the end.
They're only going to get worse.
(SPEAKS QUIETLY TO HIMSELF)
(FERAS CONTINUES RECITAL)
OK. You have been up there for
an hour and a half.
You guys look solid.
Yeah, you guys look good.
Yeah, you look good.
You're doing amazing.
Alright, shall we make it
a little more interesting?
Alright.
Those pegs are a lot sharper.
30mm each.
Now your hand positions
are very awkward.
Everyone dancing around now.
How are you going down there?
Good.
Good?
Yeah.
Night's falling, which means
the Tribal is just around the corner.
(GRIMACES)
Mark in pain now.
(WHIMPERS)
But we have seen that he has
a high pain tolerance.
Argh-argh-argh.
There's just no comfortable position
anymore.
Everything is on fire.
Wah.
Your hands, your shoulders,
your back, your legs, your feet.
(GRIMACES AND GROANS)
Lots of movement from Mark.
Grimacing now.
Stay focused, darl. You got it.
Argh.
One minute everything's fine,
and then the pain from those pegs
just catches up with you
and every part of your foot
is on fire.
(WHIMPERS)
Come on.
It won't hurt tomorrow, darl.
It won't hurt tomorrow.
(SOBS SOFTLY)
It's OK.
Just breathe.
Argh!
It's OK, it's OK.
I'm Jonathan.
Oh, yah-yah-yah.
Not yet, not yet, not yet.
I just like your name, that's all.
Jonathan LaPaglia.
Just testing out my name.
Yep.
Oww!
Deep breathing, darl.
Mark just keeps fighting.
(CRIES OUT IN PAIN)
Keep breathing.
No regrets, Mikey.
Mark looking over at Feras
and Caroline now...
..wondering just how much
they have in the tank.
After two hours and 15 minutes...
(APPLAUSE)
..and a hell of a fight...
..Mark can no longer stand the pain.
He steps out.
He is out of the challenge.
Love you, Marky Mark!
FERAS: Mark, keep your head up, bro.
(SOBS)
It's OK, babe. It's OK, darling.
You did so good. You did so good.
No one can ever say you didn't try.
It's OK.
Thanks, babe.
I love you so much.
I love you, too.
It's not over yet. OK?
Yeah.
OK. Let's go.
And now we have a showdown...
..between Feras and Caroline,
battling it out
for that final necklace
and that guarantee to be at
that final Tribal Council.
I've always fallen short
from that necklace.
I'm wearing that necklace tonight.
I'm not... I'm not stepping down.
Alright, shall we turn this
all the way up?
Yep.
Here we go.
Just get in the zone.
You got it, babe. You can do this.
Come on, guys.
Now, suddenly, it is a lot harder.
All your weight...
..going through that single
pointy peg.
Caroline looks solid.
She does.
She looks super solid.
She looks very strong.
I know Feras is in pain.
I know his face.
No, he's in a lot of pain..
Nice work, Caroline.
Lots of movement now.
Caroline skipping around
down the end there.
Looking good, sweetheart.
(GROANS SOFTLY)
That final position sure is awkward.
Oh.
Big slip from Caroline,
but she saves herself.
Nicely done.
Great recovery.
Awesome work.
Caroline finds something extra
in that tank.
Settles back in.
She's going to give Feras
a run for his money.
Feras looking pretty cool, but how
much of that is his best game face?
Caroline clearly in pain now.
Really struggling.
Argh!
You can do this.
Oh!
You want that final necklace...
..you're going to have to dig.
That necklace is the only guarantee
that you'll be there
in front of the jury.
OK, Jonathan.
That's it?
Yep.
After over two and a half hours...
..Caroline...
..has had enough.
(GROANS)
Well done.
What a performance!
Feras wins final immunity.
My God. It was so painful.
I'm so proud of you.
You've done so well.
I never doubted you, babe.
Feras, come on over.
Never thought I'd hear that name!
(CHUCKLES)
Final immunity is yours.
Guaranteed a one-in-two shot
at winning the title
and the half a million dollars
that goes with it.
You still have a big decision
to make.
Which of these two is going
to sit next to you
at the final Tribal Council?
And which of these two is going
to become our final jury member?
That's a lot to think about.
It is.
It is indeed.
I'm going to give you all a chance
to say goodbye,
and then I will see you at Tribal.
Thank you so much.
Well done.
Well done, everyone.
Well done, mate.
I love you.
I love you. I love you.
I'm going to see you tomorrow.
Yeah.
(ALL SAY THEIR GOODBYES)
I can't wait to see you.
Yeah, we'll see you tomorrow.
Bye, guys. Nice meeting you all.
Bye.
Yeah.
MARK: I'm not ready to leave.
I haven't wasted 46 days out here
to just give up
right at the final stage.
I'm not afraid of Feras.
I need to get in his head,
to influence him
to keep me around in this game.
So it's not over yet.
Wow, look at this. So small.
Nice.
Thanks, bro.
We'll now bring in the members
of our jury.
Aileen.
Jaden.
Valeria.
Alex.
Rianna.
Kitty.
Kirby.
And...
(RAYMOND LAUGHS HYSTERICALLY)
..and Raymond, voted out at the last
Tribal Council.
(LAUGHS)
So, Feras, you win your first
individual immunity,
and it felt like it was just when
you needed it the most.
Is that a fair assessment?
Yeah. I was at my absolute lowest
yesterday.
Coming so close to winning
that challenge
and losing one of my best friends.
So today my back was against
the wall
and my beautiful wife was there
to support me.
And, um, it's what got me
through it.
So if you didn't win today,
you're pretty sure you wouldn't
have been here tomorrow.
Yeah.
Almost certain.
Mark, you took that challenge
to the raggedy edge.
It felt like you were fighting
for your life in the game.
Yeah, Jonathan, I went in there
just totally focused,
trying to go for the win.
I couldn't do it.
Um, so it's disappointing.
And I've got to hand it to
the big man today.
He was unstoppable.
I seriously take my hat off to you,
mate. It was impressive.
Thank you so much, Mark.
I agree.
So, Feras, your vote is
the only one that counts.
You hold all the power.
And given the decision
you need to make tonight,
how daunting is that,
knowing what's at stake?
Yeah, it's extremely hard.
I am literally the reason why
one of these two people
aren't going to be moving forward.
Caroline, is part of you relieved
that you don't have to make
that decision tonight?
Oh.
I, um, I came so close today.
So, so close.
Like, the closest I've ever been.
And it was, like,
the most brutal challenge.
So, no, I wish that I was
in Feras's position,
and I wish that I did have
the necklace.
And, Caroline, why should Feras
take you to the end?
Feras should take me to the end
because
I can definitely hold my own
at tomorrow night's Tribal Council,
and I would love to give Feras
a run for his money.
Mark, same question.
Why should Feras take you tomorrow?
Feras has the choice right now.
He can anticipate what I would bring
to a final Tribal.
I'd put the gloves on
and we'd go at it.
Um, I think the only thing
that Feras has to consider
is that Caroline is really clever.
I'm not sure that he knows what
sort of fire Caroline will bring
to a final Tribal Council.
Wow, Feras,
you have a lot to consider.
You will decide who will be joining
that jury.
Alright, it is...
..time to vote.
It is time to vote.
Feras, you're up.
I'll go collect the vote.
Alright, I'll read the vote.
22nd person voted out...
..final member of our jury.
Mark.
You need to bring me your torch.
Well played.
Thank you so much. You did amazing.
Do your best.
Yeah.
Mark, the tribe has spoken.
Thanks, JLP. That was awesome.
Well done.
Thank you.
Alright.
You two, all the best.
It's been a pleasure to be with you
on this massive journey.
I think my life has changed forever.
So, thank you. See you soon.
Congratulations, Caroline and Feras.
You are the final two.
You have gone as far as you can go
in this game.
And tomorrow night
the power shifts to the jury.
So I suggest go home, get some sleep,
and think about how you're going
to convince them
that you deserve the title of
Sole Survivor.
Grab your torches, head back to camp.
Good luck.
Thank you so much, JLP.
Last day in Samoa.
Last day in Paradise, baby.
Oh.
It's day 47...
..and I don't think it has sunken in
yet that I'm part of the final two.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my God.
Yeah, I know. We can finally
get out of here.
Last night, I sent Mark packing
to the jury
because I felt like Caroline
would be easier to beat.
But now I'm worried that Mark
could definitely
be turning the jury against me.
So I just hope that I made
the right decision.
Have we...
Have we done our last notch?
No. Let's do that.
Yeah. Where's the machete?
Coming into this experience,
I wanted to be a very savage Feras.
Let's do it together.
In the beginning,
I was a very ruthless player.
But as the days went on, it has
really humbled me, this experience.
Hold it...
Yeah.
..and I'll help you out here.
There we go.
OK, let's go.
Yes.
That is day 47, baby.
47!
All done.
Wow.
Nah, that's crazy.
I have grown significantly.
I have become so much more patient,
so much more determined
and more emotionally intelligent.
And I think I'm going to be taking
that to the outside world.
I think it's only fitting that
a final Titan and a final Rebel,
you couldn't have picked it
any better, could you?
And, you know, I think we...
We started to realise we might have
a mix of both, you and I.
Yeah.
I've seen a bit of fire
in your eyes.
Yeah. I imagine that not a lot of
people on day one thought
that I'd still be standing here.
That's the best part about it -
proved a lot of people wrong.
Oh, well, we both did that.
Hell, yeah, we did.
There's a huge weight
on my shoulders.
I'm doing this for my religion.
I am doing this for my wife.
I'm doing this for Western Sydney.
It would mean the absolute world,
not only to win the money,
but to be the first Middle Eastern
man to win Australian Survivor.
Ohh!
Oh, look at that!
Feras! Feras!
Wow!
Coffee, milk, butter.
Oh, look at all that.
Coming into this game, as a midwife,
I was completely different from
the rest of the tribe.
"Congratulations.
"You've made it to the final two.
"Enjoy your well-earned day 47
Survivor breakfast."
Yes!
I have been up against
the strongest, the toughest,
the most strategic players
and yet I'm still here.
Cheers, my darling.
Day 47.
Wow.
I've proved you don't have
to beat them with this strength.
You've got to beat them
with this strength.
Shut...up!
It's got chocolate in it, Feras!
And that strength, determination
and strategy
is absolutely what makes me a Titan.
I actually feel myself coming alive
again.
I'm worried about that!
(CHUCKLES)
This tribe might have thought that
I was just the momma of the camp...
..but I was controlling the votes,
while making it feel like it was
a real collaboration...
Oh, smell those onions!
..and they all didn't know it.
They thought I was just bringing
the momma.
I was being a bit more than
the momma, alright.
Breakfast with a view.
Oh...wow.
Look at that.
Cheers, sweetheart.
This is what I've been waiting for.
I had the image in my head
that I was going to make it here.
I just kept focusing on that
the whole way through.
Today is like the crowning moment,
in terms of a birth and the head
coming through before the body.
You know, this is my crowning moment
in my journey here on Survivor
because I'm so close.
I'm so close and I've just got
those last final pushes to go,
and I will have birthed
what will be the biggest journey
of my life, other than giving birth
to my own three children.
How crazy is that?
Feras is underestimating me
in taking me to the end.
He doesn't know my game pre-merge
at all.
He has no idea what I'm capable of.
We're just going to have to duke
it out at this final Tribal Council,
this final culmination of
this battle
that's been going on between
the Titans and the Rebels.
I'm gonna come out swinging tonight.
Hey, JLP.
Evening.
(SIGHS)
We'll now bring in the members
of our jury.
Aileen, Jaden, Valeria, Alex,
Rianna, Kitty,
Kirby, Raymond
and Mark, voted out at the last
Tribal Council.
Hey, Marky.
Looking good.
So here we are,
day 47,
your final Tribal Council.
You two have gone as far
as you can go in this game.
And tonight the power shifts
to the jury.
Nine people you've had a hand
in voting out,
either directly or indirectly,
will now decide which of you two
deserves the title
of Sole Survivor
and the half a million dollars
that goes with it.
This is how it's going to work.
You'll each make
an opening statement.
This is your chance
to convince the jury
why you think you deserve
to win this game.
Then the jury will address you.
They'll ask you questions,
you'll answer them,
and they'll respond
in an open forum.
It might get a little ugly.
Once everyone's had their say,
the jury will then go to vote
to decide who wins this game.
OK.
So, Caroline.
Would you like to kick us off?
I would love to kick us off.
Coming into this game,
I knew that I was going to have
a target on my back from day one.
I was the oldest member
of the tribe
on a tribe of beasts.
Everyone was so strong,
so I had to create a role
for myself.
And even though
there's a whole generation
difference between us,
I felt like I formed
incredible bonds and relationships.
And that's what helped me
through the game.
Kitty, on day dot,
like, we established a bond
straightaway.
She was my number one.
And, Mark, you were my number two.
And together with Eden,
we formed the Middle-Aged Mafia.
We pulled in Val, Viola.
From there, we went into Tribe Swap,
but at this point,
I found out that
Viola was working against me
and so I had to vote Viola out.
And although it was a big move,
I knew it was the right move
because we wanted
to keep you to ourselves, Mark,
moving forward.
After merge, I think this is really
where I came into my own.
I had to really work
those relationships and bonds
and just get myself
another step ahead.
I am a person that is very loyal.
I never, ever voted
for any of my alliance,
and out of the 18 Tribal Councils
that I've attended,
there were only two of them
where I didn't know
where the vote was going.
And that was obviously you,
Kitty and Eden.
And when my back
was against the wall,
I beat Raymond
in the Firemaking Challenge.
And that's why
I'm in this position right now.
I absolutely deserve to be here
and to take that title
of Sole Survivor.
Nicely said. Feras.
Ah.
Wow, um...
Um...
I came in this game
with an aim.
To uphold my values as a person...
..as a Muslim,
as a Middle Eastern man.
I had a very, very specific
game plan that I wanted to play.
And I want to have
a bit of fun with it as well.
And I most certainly did.
I immediately recognised
that there were four alphas
in the tribe.
That is when
the alliances of misfits
came together.
Specifically Aileen,
Raymond and Garrick.
These were my rocks
throughout the game.
I never turned on these people.
I had my back against the wall
in a minority
on the new Titans tribe,
but I still stuck by
Aileen and Raymond.
Now was the time to be strategic.
And that was when
that huge move came.
We flushed out Winna's idol
and we got out Charles.
We managed to turn
that Tribal Council around.
One of the last strategic moves
that I had to make
was literally the hardest move
and that was choosing
not to save Kirby.
Kirby and I
were each other's shields
the entire time,
and we both recognised that
'cause if Kirby went,
I was next in line
and vice versa.
But then after Alex
did the whole spiel
at the Tribal Council,
I realised maybe it's time
to just put my shield down
and to show everyone
that I'm a big player as well.
And up until that point,
I haven't won
a single immunity challenge.
And at that moment,
I had to back myself.
I was prepared to either win
at that last challenge
and make it here,
or to lose and go home.
And I literally said,
"You're going to have to pull me out
in a stretcher
"because I am not stepping down."
And then lastly
came the social part of the game,
the fun part.
I just really hope
you will understand that
there is a game aspect
and a relationship aspect
that I did want to genuinely build
with you guys.
And although this is
the last Tribal Council
that we spend together,
I think it's the beginning
of a bunch of new friendships.
Alright, well...
Jury, you've heard
two very compelling pitches.
Now it's your turn
to ask the questions.
Alright, well...
Jury, you've heard
two very compelling pitches.
Now it's your turn
to ask the questions.
Mark, you want to start off?
Yeah.
Just last night, I was sitting
right next to you both,
and I was preparing my own pitch.
I'm going to give you some advice.
You need to be honest.
You need to fess up
when you have not been amazing.
That's OK.
And also, just don't overreach.
Um, just be clear and honest
and that will be your best shot.
Thanks, Mark.
So my question is to you, Caroline.
Sure.
In many parts of this game,
I was in trouble.
I was in danger,
and I got myself out of a hole.
When were you most in trouble
in this game,
and how did you get yourself
out of it?
So when I was most in trouble
in this game
was when viola
was working against me.
I got a sense during the end
of that scramble
that you were having
a lot of discussions.
And Kitty can attest to this.
I needed to protect myself.
And so I changed the votes
and that's why Viola went home.
OK. Thank you.
OK.
Aileen, what would you like to ask?
Feras.
I really, really enjoyed working
in an alliance with you.
However, I do feel like
your biggest flaw in this game
was not listening to me
or not listening
to a lot of your alliance members.
For example, the first time
you played your idol incorrectly,
when I told you you didn't
need to play it,
and the second time
was not playing it for Garrick.
Yeah.
So my question to you is,
what was a big game-altering move
that you did on your own?
Ah, look, firstly,
it's so much harder for...
..someone to make decisions
with idols.
And although I did have you
in my ear, I was just so afraid,
I guess, of playing it wrong.
For me, my strategic move
was where I chose to go
on the idol hunt,
not a feast and some socialising.
And I found this idol.
And I said,
"Alex, you hold on to it."
And that's when I shifted the target
from myself onto Alex,
because Kirby was so obsessed
with Alex's idol,
and I wanted to be
on the right side of Kirby.
So is that your big move?
Yes.
Alright, Rianna.
My question is actually going to
go to Caroline.
So you kind of just said before,
like, you're a very loyal
and trustworthy player,
and it's something you've kind of
framed your game around.
So I'm kind of just wanting
to know why,
like, when we were working together,
you still didn't really include me,
like, in the plans or, like, tell me
a fake name a bunch of times,
which I knew you guys were lying
to me about...
Twice...
Um... Twice is too many.
I guess it was working out
what that threat level was
and making sure
that I was keeping myself safe.
Yeah.
And I apologise for that.
So you're happy to go against
your own morals of the game
to get to the end?
Um... I'm... I...
There's no way that I've got
through this game
playing a completely loyal
and honest game.
I have lied.
I have deceived.
But I am an extremely loyal person.
And those people that were
in my alliance,
they definitely knew that.
OK. Thank you for your answer.
No worries.
Valeria, would you like to ask
something?
Yes. Feras...
How many votes do you think
you're going to get tonight?
Um...
I think what I learned in this game
that you can never predict
and always expect the unexpected.
To me, that's a really difficult
question.
I hope it is the majority.
Thank you. And I guess also to
Caroline.
Oh, Val, that's an amazing question.
And I can't count on any votes,
but I have adored getting to know
each and every one of you.
And I am so passionate about
this game
that I want you guys
to make your decision
based on everything
that you've heard.
Just being here is like
beyond my wildest dreams.
I think it's gonna be very hard
for the jury.
I still haven't made a decision...
..about tonight.
Sorry. What did you say?
It's gonna be very hard
for the jury.
It's a lot of beautiful words,
but I feel like it's just not
getting to the bottom,
to the nitty and gritty of things.
I mean, did everyone...?
I feel like every jury member,
including myself,
has a bit of a sour taste.
I think it's gonna be very hard
for the jury.
I still haven't made a decision.
It's a lot of beautiful words.
But I feel like it's just not
getting to the bottom,
to the nitty and gritty of things.
It's like, see, Feras,
I feel like it's not enough to call
a game a very strategic game,
when I personally haven't seen
a very strategic move.
Same with Caroline.
After a few things happened
during the game...
..it doesn't make us feel that
it was a great social game play
by Caroline.
We want the truth and we want
the ego down
and kind of show
this is how it happened.
And here I am.
I own up to not playing
the best social game.
But I tell you what, on that last
challenge yesterday, I was...
I was there with him, I beat Mark,
I have fought and grinded so hard
every single day I was out here.
So I know I've given everything.
And if you've got further questions,
I'm very happy to answer them.
Alright. Alex, what have you got?
Um, Caroline,
when I exited the game,
I challenged you that you hadn't
done enough to win.
Yeah.
And I want to know,
from when I left, how do you think
you went after that?
I think I went extremely well,
actually.
Every day, I felt like there was
a different move in the plans.
And all I needed to do was just try
and get myself another further day
in the game
so that it wasn't me voted out.
And I guess that's
where I worked myself.
I'm not sure if that answers
the question of what move you made.
Um, I guess I found that idol,
and on the night
that Kitty went home,
I had talked to everybody
and all the votes were going
on Mark.
And I put a vote on Feras,
hoping that I could save Mark,
flush Feras's idol,
and send Feras to the jury.
I thought, "This is my opportunity.
"I'm going to take it, and I'm
better to have gone and tried
"and lost than to have
never tried at all."
So that was my move.
It sounds like your big move
was playing an idol wrong,
judging from what you just said.
Kirby, what's your question?
Um, mine's to Feras.
I was always taking you
if Ri wasn't in.
Yeah.
And I told you that.
Yeah, of course.
I wasn't scared to stand next
to anyone.
Yeah.
And you also said that you weren't
scared to stand next to me.
Of course.
But you chose not to.
Yes.
So were you scared to stand with me
at the end?
Um...
Well...
Look, it was less about being scared
and more about understanding
that without you sitting here,
I had a better chance
to win Sole Survivor.
That's what it was.
Do you think you played
with the courage that you voiced?
It took a lot of courage to
stand there
and have an idol in my hands,
and although it went against
every aspect of who I am,
it was courageous for me to put
the game first,
to put down my shield of Kirby,
and to be prepared to take all
the hits.
For me, that was the most courageous
moment of the game in my eyes.
Do you know what?
I think it's extremely hard,
especially in such a fluid season
where everybody was working
with everybody
to, literally, be like,
this was purely from me.
But something
that I could definitely claim
is bluffing my idol.
I've proved that it's not just
finding an idol and playing it,
and you're safe for one
Tribal Council.
The confusion of my idol was,
in itself, a huge strategic move.
And that got me out of a lot of
possible votes
where my name could have been
written down.
Now, this idol that I held,
I had for 31 days,
and I also used that
on the last time
we could use an idol.
I wrapped up the idol
and I gave it to Ray,
and I said, "Let's plant this idol
in front of Mark,
"in front of Caroline
"so that they can see you
holding an idol."
And so not only I'm gonna be safe,
but you're also going to be safe.
I wanted Ray next to me.
That was your idea?
Yes, it was my idea.
It was definitely his idea.
And, yeah, it was pulled off.
Brilliant.
I am extremely confident in
how I've played this game.
I took out Charles.
I took out Winna.
I'm the one who sent Kirby
to the jury.
I've been at the bottom
so many times.
I've been at the top.
I've been in the middle.
And I knew when to set
the game aside
and when to just bring out Feras.
I always told myself,
leave emotions out of the game.
I was such a cutthroat player
in the beginning,
and I evolved
because I genuinely made some
friendships out here.
I did my best to represent
my culture, my religion,
my family, everything.
And this is a chance for me
to prove to my parents
that there are
so many different ways
you can make it in a place
like Australia.
You don't need to be a doctor
or an engineer or a bloody lawyer.
You can go on a TV show,
have a laugh and, um, literally
lose a bunch of challenges
and also win $500,000,
which is insane to me.
And although the title of
Sole Survivor
would make me so proud
to represent my community
as the first Middle Eastern man
to win Survivor...
..winning the $500,000 for me
is genuinely life-changing.
Alright, jury you should
have all the information you need now
to decide who you think deserves
the title of Sole Survivor
and the half million dollars
that goes with it.
Remember, tonight you are voting
for a winner.
So, for the last time...
..it is time to vote.
Alright, for the last time...
Aileen, you're up.
Ha-ha-ha.
This is not an easy decision.
You both took every opportunity
that you had.
You have both played with
an incredible amount of courage.
Congratulations to whoever wins.
Alright, I'll go count the votes.
Holy shit.
Well, there is no doubt
this has been an incredible season.
The only thing left to do
is read these votes.
But a moment like this really
should be shared
with the people you love the most.
So, come on in!
Hi, guys.
Hey, you got me.
How are you?
I'm all over the shop, yeah.
I told you I was punching, Kirby.
Punching way above my weight.
I didn't want to say anything.
You are not.
Iman...
Yeah.
So Feras has a 50-50 chance
of taking home
a half million dollars.
What would that mean for you two?
Wow, well...
Everything.
Our future.
Starting a family together.
Everything, really.
It'll mean a lot.
It'll be life-changing.
Truly.
Murray, how proud are you
of Caroline right now?
Um, Jonathan, incredibly,
you know, when she took
this on at the beginning,
I knew that she was going to give it
her best shot.
But to get to where she is now
is just quite unbelievable.
I mean, I'm really in awe.
Alright, let's get to it.
Remember, these votes are for
a winner.
I'm going to read the votes.
First vote...
..Feras.
Feras.
That's two votes, Feras.
That's three votes, Feras.
Feras.
That's four votes, Feras.
Winner of Australian Survivor,
Titans v Rebels...
..Feras.
(CHEERING)
Feras...
Here's your cheque.
Congratulations.
You are Sole Survivor,
Titans v Rebels.
Well done.
(CHEERING)
I am absolutely over the moon.
I did not for a million years think
that I could even make it
on Survivor,
let alone win the bloody game.
(CHEERING)
I'm literally still shaking.
I've been wanting to write your name
down this entire game
and it was to vote you out.
But now look at me.
I'm writing your name down
to be the Sole Survivor.
I know I grilled you a bit tonight,
but I think you are
a deserving winner.
To be the first Aussie Arab
to win Survivor
is such a huge flex.
And to show off my culture
and to show everyone
where I come from in my community
is such a huge achievement
and I'm so proud of myself.
You're an inspirational person,
mate.
South West Sydney, baby.
I think that this money
will be truly life-changing
for you and your family.
I'm looking forward to you using
1/5000th of your winnings
to buy me lunch.
I had no doubt in my mind that
a Rebel could take it home.
I was creative,
I messed with people's minds.
I made some really cool alliances
and even better rivals.
You managed to paranoid absolutely
everyone,
to hold yourself in the game
for at least, I'd say,
probably eight, nine Tribal Councils
is pretty impressive.
You had an amazing social game,
you were loyal to your alliance
and you were creative
when it came to the idol.
You deserve this 500,000, Feras.
You fooled me when you bluffed me
with the idol.
You took me on and you won.
And for that reason,
you are getting my vote.
Captions by Red Bee Media